CHRIS VALMONTE

Web Development | Web Design

chrisvalmonte.com

in linkedin.com/in/chrisvalmonte

I create web products that are usable, responsive, and delightful. With my background in computer science and interest in UI/UX design, I am passionate about making technology easier for experts and non-experts to use. My work isn't work because I love doing it. In my spare time, I enjoy playing video games, watching Disney movies, and sprinkling my design/development dust across the web.

SKILLS

Coding

HTML5

CSS3 & SCSS

JavaScript & JQuery

NodeJS

Bootstrap

Python

Ruby on Rails

Design

Object Oriented Programming Responsive Web Design Mockups & Wireframes Prototyping A11y & Usability

Toolkit

Atom
Adobe Creative Cloud
Browser Developer Tools
GitHub & Git CLI
Trello/Asana

EXPERIENCE

Code Publishing Co. **Front-End Developer**

11/2016 - 02/2018 Seattle, WA

- Based off of provided user research, applied common user interface patterns to design alternatives.
- Utilized Adobe Creative Cloud, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build innovative and responsive UI solutions for clientele.
- Developed an SCSS variable system for the customization of web interfaces, which cut development time by 33%.
- Conducted research on competitor web offerings and empathetically designed new features based on my findings.

Expedia Group Capstone Project - Team Member

09/2015 - 06/2016 Seattle, WA

- Oversaw development using Agile and Scrum.
- Created the endpoints for our REST API and consumed the API in the implementation of the map view.
- Developed 80% of the front-end for demos with stakeholders, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Seattle University **BS, Computer Science**

09/2012 - 06/2016 Seattle, WA

SELECTED PROJECTS

Hotels Now (Capstone)

- Documented and developed a fully automated web app.
- Set up schedules, delegated sprint tasks, and cleared roadblocks impeding my team.

Government Web Interfaces

Customized pixel-perfect interfaces using SCSS, including:

- bellevue.municipal.codes
- jasper.county.codes
- wiyot.tribal.codes

nwfasaisangbagsak2017.com

- Implemented a website for the NWFASA's 22nd conference.
- Saved the committee hundreds of dollars as they did not need to print programs for the event.